const e="apes_ch19",o="Chapter 19",t=[{number:1,question:"Which of the following factors have affected the earth's climate?",choices:["all of the choices","volcanoes","meteors","continental drift"],correct:0},{number:2,question:"Our climate over the past 10,000 years can best be described as",choices:["fairly stable with recent warming.","a glacial regime.","generally cooling.","fairly stable with recent cooling."],correct:0},{number:3,question:"All of the following human activities have contributed to increases in greenhouse gases except",choices:["agriculture.","deforestation.","overhunting.","burning of fossil fuels."],correct:2},{number:4,question:"The rapid rise in global mean temperatures over the past few decades could have been caused by an increase in solar output from the sun.",choices:["True","False"],correct:1},{number:5,question:"A region of the planet that has served as a large carbon sink is",choices:["Antarctica.","oceans.","deserts.","cities."],correct:1},{number:6,question:"Which of the following statements is false?",choices:["The rate of change in temperatures is as much a factor as the degree of change.","Scientists are more concerned with local weather patterns than with global changes in climate.","We will have to do with the impacts of climate change in our lifetimes.","Climate change may reach the point where reversing its impacts may be impossible for an extremely long period of time."],correct:1},{number:7,question:"In terms of water, the earth is currently experiencing",choices:["an increase in soil moisture.","more widespread drought conditions.","in increase in available surface water.","shrinking deserts."],correct:1},{number:8,question:"Predicted impacts from global warming include all of the following except",choices:["more extreme weather.","lowering sea levels.","species extinctions.","melting icecaps."],correct:1},{number:9,question:"A species immediately impacted by global warming is the",choices:["panda bear.","black bear.","grizzly bear.","polar bear."],correct:3},{number:10,question:"Which of the following factors describes the impacts of climate change?",choices:["Both the problem and the solution involve politics.","Everyone is affected uniformly.","Reducing the impacts will not be expensive.","The effects will be short-term."],correct:0},{number:11,question:"The dirtiest fossil fuel is",choices:["petroleum.","uranium.","coal.","natural gas."],correct:2},{number:12,question:"The most notable country not providing support for the Kyoto Protocol was",choices:["India.","the United States.","Japan.","Brazil."],correct:1},{number:13,question:"The amount of carbon generated by your lifestyle is known as your",choices:["environmental consciousness.","carbon capture storage (CCS) unit.","species impact.","carbon footprint."],correct:3},{number:14,question:"The atmospheric ozone layer that shields the earth from the sun is found in the",choices:["troposphere.","thermosphere.","mesosphere.","stratosphere."],correct:3},{number:15,question:'The so-called "ozone hole" appears strongest each year above',choices:["North America.","Australia.","the poles.","Africa."],correct:2},{number:16,question:"Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) have been used as all of the following except",choices:["cleaners.","coolants.","fuel for cars.","propellants"],correct:2},{number:17,question:"Ozone thinning can lead to more occurrences of skin cancer, the worst of which is",choices:["basal cell carcinoma.","squamous cell carcinoma.","Ozone thinning will not increase the occurrences of any type of skin cancer.","melanoma."],correct:3},{number:19,question:"Stratospheric ozone depletion can never be reversed.",choices:["false","true"],correct:0}],r={id:e,displayName:o,questions:t};export{r as default,o as displayName,e as id,t as questions};
